In Jesus' name I pray, amen.
I'm gonna sit on a stool today
because I do not feel very well.
And that's the story.
And so it's a great reminder
that the Holy Spirit does not need me to be energetic
to speak through me to you.
And so that's my prayer this morning
that we would hear from him.
Hey, being a father has opened me up
to many new experiences
and a whole new world of information.
When you become a parent,
you're exposed to things
that you never would have been exposed to before.
I have been experiencing that
for about a year and a half now.
One of those new experiences
that have impacted me greatly
is an Australian TV show by the name of Bluey.
Some of you may be familiar.
And if you are not, I am sorry.
It is your loss.
From the outside looking in,
it is a silly show for kids
about a young blue healer puppy and her family.
Yes, her family.
My dad found out it was a girl
and he was very upset.
But once you get enveloped into the family,
you quickly realize that in my opinion,
it is a cinematic masterpiece
filled with lighthearted fun for the kids
and deep philosophical reflections
for the life or for the parents.
One such episode of Cinematic Masterpiece
is an episode called Born Yesterday.
Anybody?
Are my parents in the room?
All right, Born Yesterday.
The dad pretends that he was born yesterday
and he is experiencing everything for the first time.
It's obviously goofy for the kids.
They're walking him all around
and teaching him about what the sun is
and why you shouldn't just walk up to strangers
and eat their food.
Goofy for the kids,
but it has deep rooted meaning for adults.
At the end of the episode,
after the game is over
and the dad has stopped playing,
the mom looks out into the backyard
and the son is, or the father,
sorry, I gotta do my do not disturb.
My group chat's going off.
Somebody.
The wife looks out
and the dad is sitting out in the grass by himself,
marveling at the beauty of creation all around him,
the creation that he walks by
every single day without noticing.
But just that few minutes of a game
of making him look at everything
like he's looking at it for the first time
opened up his eyes to the beauty all around him.
Approaching familiar things from a fresh perspective
can often lead us to a deeper appreciation.
And that's what I wanna do with communion this morning
because my guess is that there's really two groups
of people in the room this morning.
There are people who are newer to faith
who have kind of been outside the church looking in
and have found a home here.
And my guess is for you,
communion feels a bit strange,
but everybody else seems to be comfortable with it.
So you've just learned to go along with the flow
and not ask any questions.
And then for a lot of others of us,
we're longtime believers
or what I like to call church folk
because for whatever reason, that's how you say it.
And we have become familiar
with participating in communion
and maybe we even have a shallow understanding of it.
We have kind of just adopted
whatever we were taught as children.
We haven't really thought about it
for ourselves in a long time
and we've lost our appreciation and wonder
around what is so beautiful and great about communion.
So that's my goal
is that we'd look at it from a fresh perspective.
And for those of you who have been too afraid
to ask what's going on with this whole thing
because it seems strange to you,
but everyone else thinks it's normal,
hopefully this will help you understand
what it is exactly we are doing in communion.
And for those of us that have grown up in the church
and we've become familiar with it
or we've just embraced whatever theology
about communion was handed to us,
I hope that taking this fresh look
will invite you into a deeper experience
at the table this morning and moving forward.
Does that sound like a good plan?
All right, so the outline for this morning
is what is communion exactly?
And then why of all the things,
and this was the question that I actually received
from the survey of the frequently asked questions
was of all the things Jesus could have asked us to do
on a regular basis, why communion?
It seems strange, it seems odd.
And then how should we approach the table?
What is communion?
Why did Jesus give it to us?
And how should we participate in it?
And again, I personally,
I thought when I got this question
that it was gonna be a softball for me, right?
I've grown up in the church.
I know what communion is.
I know about communion.
I take communion, I've led communion services.
It should be an easy message for me to prepare.
But the more that I studied,
the more I realized that communion is much bigger
and more beautiful than I've often given it credit for.
And so my hope, my prayer is that that will happen
for many of us in the room this morning.
What exactly is communion?
Well, communion is one of the two primary ordinances
or sacraments given by God to the church.
Some expressions of the church throughout history
have emphasized more than two,
but the majority of the church throughout all of history
has agreed on two primary ordinances.
An ordinance is just a specific practice
given to the church by God to do together.
The first is baptism.
It's a one-time ordinance for new believers
to do in front of their church community.
The thing that I love about both ordinances
is that it is both an individual and a corporate act
because Christianity is not an individual faith.
It is a corporate faith.
We do this thing together.
So when we do baptisms,
which we're going to do later in November,
individuals are going to participate
in the act of baptism,
the ordinance, the sacrament of baptism,
and we are going to be observers
and celebrators of that
because we are in this together with them.
The second is communion.
It is a repetitive practice for the church
to do regularly with one another in community.
I love what this old dead guy says about sacraments.
His name's Thomas Watson.
He says a sacrament is a visible sermon.
It is a physical action
that invites individuals and communities
to participate in spiritual truths.
I've often said I love when we do communion
at the end of services that I preach
because even if I totally botch the message,
you will be able to see the beauty and grace of Jesus
in the bread and the cup.
Communion is a great way to save a bad sermon.
So in order to succinctly answer this question,
what exactly is communion?
I think what I want to do
is I want to go over the five titles
that the Bible uses for communion
and draw out some applications.
I'm going to try and go through these quickly, hopefully,
because I want to get some more time
in the why and the how.
So five titles we find in Scripture for communion.
The first is the Lord's Supper.
We see this in 1 Corinthians 11, verse 20.
When you meet together, Paul says,
you are not really interested in the Lord's Supper.
We're going to get to the Corinthians in a little bit.
Paul doesn't seem very happy with him,
but this is a title that the early church uses for communion.
What's beautiful about the Lord's Supper
is that what Jesus does in the Lord's Supper
is he institutes a new meal
that replaces a very familiar meal
to the Jewish community.
See, when Jesus first ordained the act of communion,
he did so on the night
where him and his followers were celebrating Passover.
Jesus in the Lord's Supper
is moving forward God's redemptive plan
from Israel to the church.
Jesus meticulously crafted this final meal with his disciples.
If you've ever read the story
about the night that the Lord's Supper happened
for the first time,
it's kind of like a spy movie.
Jesus tells his disciples,
like, hey, go into this town
and look for a guy with a pot
and follow him
and all of the stuff's gonna be set up, right?
It's, like, really cryptic.
But, like, it shows that Jesus
put so much thought and preparation
into setting up this Passover meal
so that he could redefine for his disciples.
Right before he went to the cross,
he could redefine for them
what this meal was all about.
The Lord's Supper was moving forward
God's redemptive plan
from the old covenant to the new covenant.
Passover was all about looking back to Yahweh,
freeing Israel from slavery in Egypt
and awaiting their ultimate savior
promised by their prophets.
Jesus takes this meal
and he transforms it into a new meal,
the Lord's Supper.
And this emphasizes the ultimate fulfillment
of God's saving work.
When Jesus instituted the Lord's Supper,
he was saying,
your awaited salvation has come through me.
I am the ultimate Passover lamb
who won't just bring earthly salvation
to Israel from physical enemies,
but I will bring eternal salvation
to the whole world from spiritual enemies.
Jesus moving forward,
the redemptive plan of God.
It reimagines what salvation really is all about.
And it looks forward to his future salvation.
In Passover, Passover looked backwards
to God setting Israel free from Egypt
and it looked forward to a coming Messiah.
Communion, the Lord's Supper,
it has both a looking back and a looking forward.
Now we look back to Jesus who is our Passover lamb
and we look forward to the marriage supper of the lamb
when Jesus will return
and he will have this meal with us once again.
Listen to it in Matthew chapter 26, verse 29.
Jesus says,
So the Lord's Supper communion,
it's about looking backwards to the cross,
what Jesus did through his death, burial, and resurrection.
It's about thinking that he is the new Passover lamb,
the Passover lamb that became the sacrifice for our sins once and for all.
And it's also about looking forward to a future salvation.
We're getting ready to turn our attention to Advent.
And Advent is all about if Jesus came the first time like the prophets promised,
then he will come the second time like he promised us.
The Lord's Supper is both a looking back and a looking forward.
It demonstrates God's plan of salvation through Jesus,
the ultimate Passover lamb.
It unifies the old and new covenants
and prophetically looks forward to his final salvation
when he will bring heaven to earth once and for all.
Second title of communion in the Scriptures is the breaking of bread.
We see this in Acts 2, 42.
It says,
They devoted themselves to the apostles' teaching and to fellowship
and to the breaking of bread and to prayer.
Almost all theologians believe that this title,
breaking of bread, was a title for communion.
It doesn't really make sense to say fellowship and breaking of bread
unless the breaking of bread signified something specific
and tangible that they were doing.
This title, breaking of bread,
it emphasizes Christ's sacrificial death to secure our salvation
and join us together in a new multi-ethnic family of God
from every tribe, language, and tongue.
Jesus, when he instituted this meal,
he took the bread and he broke it.
He said,
This is my body, which is broken for you.
This title reminds us of the cost that this meal took
in order to be instituted,
that Christ's body had to be broken for us
in order for us to be invited to this table.
God made Jesus, who knew no sin,
to be an offering for our sins
so that we can sit at the table.
We can come to the table and receive grace and mercy and forgiveness
and reconciled relationships with one another.
Breaking of bread reminds us that Christ is hosting a meal
and he's inviting you to the table
and the cost of that meal was his very life.
Think about, I mean, just think about how much it means to you,
unless you're like the most introverted human being of all time.
Think about how much it means to you
when someone invites you over to their home for a meal.
Think about how significant it is.
You get there and they've totally prepared everything.
They've thought about everything.
They've answered all of your questions.
They've got appetizers, right?
Like it just makes you feel loved, accepted, wanted.
And this is what Jesus is doing at communion,
except the cost of the meal with his very own body and blood.
Jesus is inviting you to his table
and he was willing to pay the ultimate sacrifice.
And this is one of those ones,
I love emphasizing the communal aspect of communion,
but this is one of those ones
I really want you to think about personally.
Jesus, his body was broken and his blood was shed
so that you could be invited to this table.
Like personalize that for a minute.
I don't know about you, but I tend to think,
yeah, Jesus loved the whole world.
No, Jesus loved you.
And he invites you to this table
at the cost of his very body and blood.
The breaking of bread, the Lord's Supper.
I skipped three slides.
That's not good.
Number three, the Eucharist.
Anybody grow up with this title, Eucharist?
Okay, it's a bit fancier.
Nothing to be afraid of.
Just comes from the Greek word for thanksgiving.
In 1 Corinthians 11, verse 23,
for I pass on to you what I received.
The Lord himself on the night when he was betrayed,
he took some bread and he gave thanks to God for it.
Then he broke it.
Eucharist just comes from the Greek word for thanksgiving.
It reminds us that the communion table,
the Lord's Supper was instituted
at the end of a very long meal around a table.
There's things to give thanks for.
And although there are somber undertones
on the night of the first communion,
Jesus gave thanks.
This is something that we can do
with celebration in our hearts.
We give thanks to God for who Jesus is
and for what he did.
Communion is intended to be reflective,
but it's also intended to be filled with thanksgiving.
Jesus gave thanks for the opportunity
to participate in this meal with one another.
We should be thankful when we come to the table.
We should look around the room
and give thanksgiving for the people
that God has brought around this table.
In many churches I have been a part of
and even communions that I have led
sometimes tend to overemphasize
the weightiness of communion.
And I think that's important.
That's an important element,
but it's both and.
It's something that we should have joyful attitudes
in our heart towards
that we should have thanksgiving for.
So we've got the Lord's Supper,
the breaking of bread, Eucharist,
the weirdest one of all, the love feast.
Everybody loves the love feast.
We see this in Jude 12.
If you've never read Jude before, don't worry.
I'm sure you're not alone.
I heard one pastor call it
one of the Bible's deep tracks,
which I thought was awesome.
Do yourself a favor, read Jude sometime,
but they use this term, the love feast,
to refer to communion.
And this term for communion is one
that has been used historically
by the expression of churches
that we are a part of.
The Brethren Church, the Anabaptist Church
have often used this term, the love feast.
The reason they do that
is because they have intentionally chosen
to include both a meal and,
drum roll please.
Thank you, thank you.
Foot washing with the bread and the cup.
Much of, so they, this love feast
is kind of this all-encompassing,
a full meal, the bread broken,
the cup shared, and then a foot washing.
And much of the church throughout history
has viewed Christ's invitation to wash feet
as kind of this cultural expression
of sacrificial love,
that Jesus is inviting us
to be sacrificially loving towards one another,
and the foot washing thing
was just a cultural example that he used.
But, what if it was actually an invitation
for all believers throughout history
to practice the most challenging aspect
of the Christian life,
which is to humbly serve
and to be served?
Listen to Jesus in John chapter 13.
On this night that he instituted the Lord's Supper,
after he washed his disciples' feet,
he says this,
if I then, your Lord and teacher,
have washed your feet,
you also ought to wash one another's feet.
For I have given you an example
that you also should do just as I have done to you.
Truly, truly, I say to you,
a servant is not greater than his master,
nor is a messenger greater than the one who sent him.
If you know these things,
blessed are you who do something like them.
Okay, blessed are you if you do them.
Now, I don't have time to give this view justice,
and we have actually intentionally planned
an entire special service
around giving this view justice.
There should be an insert in your flyer.
I would love for you,
if this interests you at all,
even if it doesn't interest you at all,
if you think this is crazy,
I would challenge you,
I would even dare you
to come to our fall feast.
We are bringing in a brethren theologian,
a seminary professor
who is far smarter than I could ever be,
and he is going to talk
about the significance of the love feast,
of why our churches historically
have included a full meal
and a foot washing
in at least one or two communions a year.
We're gonna share a meal together.
We're gonna listen to a teaching
from a theological scholar.
I know some of you love the heady stuff.
Dare you, I dare you.
I don't know if you can tell,
but I'm nervous about people coming to this thing,
so I'm daring everybody.
I dare you.
And what we're gonna do
is we're gonna share a meal together.
We're gonna listen to a teaching,
and we're going to have an opportunity
to wash feet.
It will be optional.
So you can come for the meal
and the teaching,
and then you can just
watch other people wash feet,
which might be weirder than washing feet.
I'm not sure.
And this is a very new cultural experience
for a lot of us.
All I can tell you
is from personal experience,
I have participated
in a few foot washing services,
and they are some of the most powerful,
moving, emotional, challenging services
I've ever been a part of.
So I don't have time to do it justice.
Someone else is gonna do it justice
in a few weeks.
Please make plans to attend.
Finally, communion.
Communion is probably my favorite term
for the Lord's Supper.
It comes from 1 Corinthians 10,
verses 16 and 17.
Paul says,
when we bless the cup at the Lord's table,
are we not sharing in the blood of Christ?
Let's not read past that.
That's a significant,
that is a significant claim of Paul.
Are we not sharing in the blood of Christ?
And when we break the bed,
are we not sharing in the body of Christ?
The Greek word there for sharing,
many other translations use communion.
It is koinonia.
This is deeply,
this is a deep and intimate participatory word.
We are invited to commune with one another
and with the body and blood of Christ
in some supernatural and mysterious way.
This is significant.
In the Western church,
we struggle with understanding
how spiritual things and physical things overlap.
Am I the only one?
We often consider them separate spheres
that don't overlap with one another.
This is platonic and not biblical, okay?
So when we take communion,
we are invited into an intimate time of fellowship
with God and with one another.
We are reminded that even when we struggle
to get along or be united,
look at verse 17.
And though we are many,
we all eat from one loaf of bread
showing that we are one body.
So no matter how hard relationships get in this room,
especially around election time,
no matter how many external factors
cause us to want to divide from one another,
we are invited to come to the same table
and take from the same loaf of bread,
which is a representation that we are one body,
unified around Christ,
body broken for us and his blood shed for us.
If we can't unify on anything else,
God help us if we can't unify
on the death, burial, and resurrection of Jesus.
Let's say that communion is a physical,
spiritual, and prophetic remembering
of Christ's body with Christ's body.
Something we do physically
that has spiritual implications and future prophetic.
We're looking forward to the return of Christ.
When we participate in remembering Christ's body
with Christ's body.
Which leads us to the why of communion.
And this was the thrust of the question I received.
I loved it.
It was so great.
She said,
of all of the ordinances,
of all the things Jesus could have asked us to do
on a regular basis,
why not like remember the poor together
on a regular basis?
Why this meal?
What's so significant about communion?
And as I thought about this particular question,
pastorally,
like,
Jesus,
what are you trying to do here for us?
What is the significance
of this thing being a primary thing
that you invite your people to do?
I realized that it is very easy for me,
probably just me,
only me,
I'm sure,
to become distracted
and to feel disconnected
from God and from one another.
I don't know about you,
but it's my experience
with most of my friend groups
and family members
that life is so fast-paced and busy.
It's so easy for us to become distracted.
It's so easy for us to feel disconnected
from God and one another.
God is not visible.
He's not tangible.
We can't sit in a chair beside him.
And so it's so easy for us
to feel disconnected from God.
People are frustrating and difficult.
They rarely do what we want them to do
or say what we want them to say.
And when relationships become difficult,
it can be easier just to let them go
than to fight for them.
And this often leads us
into isolation or echo chambers.
When relationships become hard,
we just let them go.
And that either means
that we're all by ourself
or we're all by ourself
with a group of people
that think exactly like we think,
believe exactly like we believe,
do things exactly the way we do them.
And I think communion is given to us
as a solution to these problems
because imagine how powerful
a group of diverse people
united around and submitted
to the slain lamb
who was victorious over sin,
death, and the grave
could have on the world around them
that is so distracted and disconnected.
If we were not distracted or disconnected,
imagine the witness to the watching world
that we could have.
And I think that's one
of the primary reasons
that Jesus gave us communion.
He gave it to us
to fight against distraction
and to fight against disconnecting
from God and from one another.
So first, let's unpack distraction.
In communion, Jesus brings forward
the beautiful rhythm
seen in the Jewish calendar.
The Jewish culture was built
around regular religious festivals
that were intended
every single year,
year in and year out,
to remind them
of God's faithful love for them.
Passover was probably
the primary
of the religious festivals.
It was to root them
in the history
of God's redemptive work
in their people.
And when Jesus invites the church
to replace that
with this regular rhythm
of gathering around the table together,
to remember his sacrificial love,
he's bringing forth
this rhythm,
this repetition,
something that we should do
intentionally and regularly.
it's meant to keep our eyes
focused on the main thing,
not to get distracted
by the worries
or cares of this world
that all find their meaning
and purpose in Jesus.
Communion is meant
to be a regular rhythm
that keeps us
from getting distracted.
We are so prone to wander.
We are so prone
to make things other
than Christ,
the center of our theology.
We are so prone
to divide over things
other than what is primary
to divide over.
And communion invites us
to regularly keep our eyes
focused on Christ's body
and his blood.
It's intended to keep us
from getting distracted.
from feeling disconnected
from Jesus.
I cannot read this passage
in 1 Corinthians 10 enough,
and I just invite you
to wrestle with it.
When we bless the cup
at the Lord's table,
are we not sharing
in the blood of Christ,
having communion,
koinonia with the blood
of Christ?
And when we break the bread,
aren't we sharing in,
having communion,
koinonia, fellowship,
intimacy with the body
of Christ?
Communion is intended
to give us
this connection
to Jesus.
Because we can't touch
or see God,
it can be easy
to feel disconnected
from him.
But the Christian faith,
excuse me,
the Christian faith
is not only
a communal faith,
but it's also
an embodied faith.
The Christian faith
is a whole person faith.
We are physical
human beings,
and we tend
to separate
the spiritual
and the physical,
but that is not
a biblical concept.
The Bible seems
to claim
that we get
some kind of,
we can somehow
physically experience
the presence of Christ
through the elements
of communion
when we come
to them in faith.
This koinonia language
is radical.
In the church,
for the first
thousand years,
we're united
around the mystery
that somehow,
in some mysterious way,
Jesus chooses
to be present
in the elements
of communion
when a group
of believers
take them
in faith.
Now,
for those of you
that are theology nerds,
that maybe have come
from the Catholic Church,
I know that you're
probably feeling
slightly uncomfortable
right about now.
That's okay.
You're allowed
to feel that way.
And I wanna be careful
because we rational
Western Christians
are not great
with mystery.
We don't do good
with not having
answers to our questions.
We want logical answers
that fit into
clean theological systems.
But if you go back
and you read
Christ's interactions
with his disciples,
he seems to be
pretty okay
with not giving them
all of the answers
to all of their questions.
He seems to be
pretty okay
with letting them
just experience
the mystery
of his kingdom
and he gives them
the answers
that they need
when they need them.
But there's mystery,
there's beauty
in the Christian faith.
And I think
many streams
of Christianity
like the one
I grew up in
were comfortable
shrinking communion
down to purely
just a physical symbol,
just an illustration,
just a reminder.
The more I read
the Scriptures
and think about this idea,
the more I'm concerned
that we might be
missing out
on some depth
and beauty
of what Jesus
wants us
to experience
in communion.
I'm not going
to answer
the theological question
of whether or not
Christ is present
in the communion elements
when he becomes present,
what that looks like.
That's when the church
started to divide.
They started to divide
when they started
to try and answer
what exactly it means.
All I know
is that Christ says,
that Paul says here
in 1 Corinthians,
that we are somehow
sharing in Christ's blood.
We are somehow
sharing having
koinonia with Christ's body.
And I'm not going
to try and explain that.
I don't know
what that means.
But I think
we should come
to the communion table
a bit more expectantly
than this is just
some random wafer
that I'm going to take
and remember Christ's body.
Let's come expectantly
to the table.
And in here,
again,
this is the,
okay.
our church,
we don't have
a clear position
on what exactly
this means.
We don't define it
because the most
heartbreaking thing
about communion
is that it is
the one thing,
the primary thing
that was intended
to unite us
and it has become
a thing that has
divided many churches
throughout history.
There are multiple
different tables
and denominations
of people that can
and cannot participate
in communion,
even if they've
submitted to the
lordship of Jesus
because we define
communion differently
than you define
communion.
I'm not trying
to make a clear
definition here.
I'm just trying
to say,
what if Jesus
wants something
more for us
at the table?
I'd invite you
individually,
prayerfully,
consider what God
might want to do
for you
in giving you
some mystery
of his real
presence
with you
in the communion
elements
when you come
with expectant
faith.
We feel
disconnected
from God,
we feel
disconnected
from one another.
Again,
the more I've
studied this week,
the more heartbroken
I have become
over church history
because,
again,
the thing
that Jesus
gave us
to unite us
with one another
has become
a tool
that the enemy
has used
to divide us.
and it
didn't start
that far
after Jesus
instituted it.
Let's look
at the
Corinthian church,
right?
1 Corinthians 10
verse 17,
but in the
following instructions,
I cannot praise you
for it sounds
as if more harm
than good
is done
when you meet
together.
For I hear
that there are
divisions among you
when you meet
as a church
and to some
extent I believe it
but of course
there must be
divisions among you
so that you
who have God's
approval
will be
recognized.
When you
meet together
you are
not really
interested
in the
Lord's
supper.
For some
of you
hurry to
eat your
own meal
without sharing
with others
and as a
result some
go hungry
while others
get drunk.
Don't you
have your
own homes
for eating
and drinking
or do you
really want
to disgrace
God's church
and shame
the poor?
What am I
supposed to
say to you?
Do you
want me
to praise
you?
I will
certainly
not praise
you for
this.
The thing
that's
supposed to
unite us
so quickly
becomes a
thing that
divides us
in the
Corinthian
churches
they were
breaking
into
factions
and they
were
prioritizing
people
who had
status
and
influence
around
the
communion
table.
What they
were doing
might have
resembled
communion
but Paul
seems to
warn them
that this
isn't
actually
communion
at all.
See the
patterns of
table fellowship
in the early
Christian church
it was one
of the most
radical things
about them.
Table fellowship
was so
significant in
the first
century.
Who was
allowed around
your table
and when people
walked by
your house
and they
saw who
was sitting
at your
table
they would
make very
clear distinctions
about what
was true
about you.
And the
early Christian
church was
radical about
welcoming people
from every
tribe,
language,
and tongue.
Jesus was
known as a
drunkard
and a
sinner
because he
ate with
tax collectors
and sinners.
Communion was
intended that
we were all
welcome around
the table
together.
Everyone is
equal at the
foot of the
cross.
Everyone from
every social,
economic,
or racial
class, we are
all welcomed
at the table.
We are all
invited to take
from the same
bread and cup.
Communion is
intended to
regularly remind
us what unites
us.
It's far more
important than
the cultural
factors that
attempt to
divide us.
Everyone who
submits to
Jesus is at
equal standing
at the
table.
So, in
summary, why
do we take
communion?
I would say
that communion
is an
intentional,
embodied rhythm
that connects
us physically
with Jesus
and with
one another.
I was very
intentionally
vague in
that definition
so that we
can all come
to our own
conclusions about
what exactly
that looks
like.
So, finally,
how?
How do we
come to the
communion table?
Well, I think
it's really
important that
what communion
is and why
Jesus gave it
to us should
impact how
we participate.
So, I
crammed four
things into a
three-thing list
because I'm
trying to get
better at
preaching not
as long.
So, we'll
see how this
goes.
The first,
when we
approach the
communion table,
we should do
so reflectively.
1 Corinthians 10
verse 27,
Paul gives
these instructions
to the
Corinthians who
were just not
even really
taking communion.
They were
taking something
that looked
like communion,
but it had
so been
removed from
the point of
what Jesus
gave it to
them for that
Paul says,
you're not
even really
concerned with
the Lord's
Supper.
He gives them
these instructions.
So, anyone
who eats this
bread or drinks
this cup of
the Lord
unworthily is
guilty of sinning
against the
body and
blood of
Jesus.
That is
why you
should examine
yourself before
eating the
bread and
drinking the
cup.
We should
come to
communion
reflectively.
We should
allow it to
be a regular
rhythm for
us to come
before the
presence of
God and
to be honest
about where
we're at in
our relationship
with him.
This does
not mean,
and this is
the type of
communion that
I grew up
with,
this does
not mean
that if
you sinned
last night,
you shouldn't
come to the
table.
It's an
invitation to
reflect on
your life and
consider the
sin and
broken relationships
that have
creeped into
your life and
acknowledge those
before God and
receive his
grace and
mercy with
thanksgiving.
There is
something significant
about broken
relationships though
in communion.
I think it is
this opportunity
for us to
reflect on who
in the church,
who of our
brothers and
sisters in
Christ do we
have something
against?
Who have we
gossiped about?
slandered about?
Who have we
gotten fights
with and
not forgiven?
I think that
communion is
an opportunity
for us to
think about
the reconciliation
that needs to
happen before
we participate
in the body
and blood of
Jesus.
I love what
Pastor Sam
Rogers, he's
been here to
preach a couple
times, a good
friend of mine.
I consider him
my pastor.
He preached on
communion and he
said this,
if you feel
conviction, it
means that you're
ready for the
table because a
person who is
not close to
God does not
have a problem
with their sin.
So do so
reflectively, but
as you are
confronted with
your sin, with
your struggle, with
your failures before
God, this is not
something to feel
shame or guilt, this
is something to give
to the Lord in
confession and
repentance and
come to the table
eagerly and
expectantly for his
grace and mercy to
flow over you.
So reflectively,
second, regularly and
corporately, this is
where I fit two
into one.
We shouldn't let
communion become an
isolated experience
and this is the
reality of the
American church is
that it's hard to do
communion in a way
that really resembles
the first century
church.
We sit in rows, we
come and we get
little wafers and
little juice and
communion made it,
or communion,
COVID made it even
harder.
But we should do
our best as much as
we can to make sure
that it doesn't just
become a you and God
experience, it is a
communal experience.
We should look around
the room with
thanksgiving of all of
the people that God
has brought into this
room specifically.
We should do so
corporately.
regularly.
Again, the American
church makes this step
difficult.
We do our best to have
it pretty frequently
here at Canvas and
we could definitely do
better at making it
more regular and more
corporate.
I'm going to think
about this more often
and how we can be
creative with this.
But I would say,
don't just limit your
experience of communion
to Sunday.
Some of the most
powerful experiences I
have had around the
body of Christ, the
blood of Christ has
been in living rooms
with small groups of
people.
Think about when you
meet together with
other brothers and
sisters in Christ,
how you might
remember Christ's body
broken for you and
his blood shed.
Do so regularly, do
so corporately, and
lastly, do so
expectantly.
I think many of us,
myself, at the top of
this list, have become
so familiar with
communion that it's
lost some of its
mystery and its
beauty.
We should come to the
table with expectation
of whatever it is that
Paul means by
koinonia with Christ's
body and koinonia with
Christ's blood.
Again, I'm not going to
define what that means,
but that's what the
text says, that there
is some type of
communion, some type of
fellowship with Christ's
body and blood when we
come to the table
expectantly.
I heard Francis Chan
talking about this on a
podcast this week, and he
used the illustration of
the woman who had been
bleeding for 12 years in
Luke chapter 8, and he
said, I like to think
about this in communion,
when people are so used to
just coming to it like
it's a symbol, and he's
like, I've talked to
people who have now
reimagined what God
might want to do in
koinonia with his body
and blood, and they said
that their experiences
have changed at the
communion table, that
there's something
mysterious and
supernatural that
happens at the
communion table for them
now, that they come to
it expectantly, that
they come to it
differently.
And he said it
reminds him of the
woman who was bleeding
for 12 years.
You read that story, and
there's a mob of people
everywhere, and this woman
reaches out and touches
Jesus in faith, and Jesus
says, whoa, whoa, whoa,
everybody stop.
Somebody touched me.
And what do his disciples
say?
Yeah, everybody's touching
you, Jesus.
Like, we are in a crowded
street full of people.
Everyone is touching you.
And Jesus says, no,
someone touched me with
faith.
Someone reached out to
me with intention, with
purpose.
And I just, I love that
illustration.
I think that there's
something unique, something
special that Jesus might
want to do for those of us
who come to the
communion table expecting
something more than just
the mental exercise of
remembering his
sacrifice.
Something supernatural.
Again, I'm not a
charismatic person.
I don't know what that
means.
I'm just trying to be
faithful to the text, and
the text seems to say
that God wants to do
something in you and
through you at the
communion table.
Koinonia, fellowship
with his body, fellowship
with his blood.
So, hopefully, this
message has helped all
of us increase or deepen
our understanding of what
communion is, why Jesus
preserved it for us, and
how we should approach
the table.
I hope this fresh
perspective will deepen
your appreciation for this
important ordinance.
If what I have said has
caused more questions than
answers, send me the
email, but it's caused more
questions than answers for
me as well.
And I think that Jesus is
okay with that.
I think sometimes the
Christian faith is mysterious
and supernatural, and we so
want every answer.
We so want to check every
box.
And I'm just, I'm
comfortable right now with
saying, I'm not going to
check this box.
I'm just going to start
coming more reflectively,
more regularly and
corporately, and more
expectantly that God might do
something exceedingly,
abundantly, more than I could
ever ask, think, or imagine
through a stale piece of
bread and probably out-of-date
juice.
Don't quote me on that.
Jesus can heal a leopard if
he can turn a little boy's
lunch into a meal for 5,000
people.
What might he be able to do
for us if we come to it in
faith with this little wafer
and this little cup of juice?
Let's pray.